Ernst W. Caspari Papers 1932-1980 Mss.Ms.Coll.1
American Philosophical Society
- Ernst W. Caspari Papers, 1932-1980; 9.5 lin. feet
  - Committee of Concerned Scientists, 1976-1979 (Box 7)
  - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Contemporary Psychology, 1960-1961 (Box 7)
    Review: Behavior Genetics, Fuller and Thompson.
  - Corn, Mary L., 1970 (Box 7)
  - Corson, Stephen, 1960-1964 (Box 7)
  - Cotter, William B., 1956-1977; 4 folders (51 items) (Box 7)
    Biographical and personal data; Genetics -- Ephestia; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; University of Kentucky
  - Cowgill, U. M., 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Crews, Frederick, 1966-1967 (Box 7)
  - Creyhton, Harriet B., 1972 (Box 7)
  - Crick, Francis H. C. (Box 7)
  - Culbertson, Michael R., 1971 (Box 7)
  - Cummings, Michael R., 1970 (Box 7)
  - Dalton, Clark, 1948-1970; 3 folders (59 items) (Box 7)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Embryology, developmental genetics; Genetics -- Ephestia; New York University; Publication
  - Danielli, James F., 1980 (Box 7)
  - David, Henry, 1968-1974 (Box 7)
  - DeFries, J. C., 1969 (Box 7)
  - Delano, Erwin, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Demerec, Milislav, 1940-1963; 4 folders (80 items) (Box 7)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Publication; Radiation genetics; Russian politics and science
  - Demerec, Milislav et al. Re: nomenclature in bacterial genetics, 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Dessauer, Friedrich, 1959 (Box 7)
  - DNA legislation, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Doane, Winifred W., 1979 (Box 7)
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1961-1971; 2 folders (36 items) (Box 7)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biographical and personal data; Editorial matters; Evolution; Genetics; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Dronmraju, K. R., 1967-1971 (Box 7)
    Jameson, David L.
  - Dubinin, N. P., 1967 (Box 7)
  - Dunn, L. C. (Leslie Clarence), 1939-1971; 4 folders (71 items) (Box 8)
    Biographical and personal data; Editorial matters; Genetics; Mouse genetics; Publication; Recommendations
  - Ebata, Yuichi, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Egelhaaf, Albrecht, 1957-1978; 5 folders (112 items) (Box 8)
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Editorial matters; Genetics -- Ephestia; Kuhn, Alfred; Publication; Recommendations; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; University of Koln
  - Ehrman, Lee Rothschild, 1962-1975; 27 items (Box 8)
    Biographical and personal data; Genetics -- Ephestia; Publication; Recommendations
  - "On the etiology of sterility of hybrids between certain strains of Drosophila paulistorum.", Williamson, D.L. (Box 8)
    Williamson, D. L.
  - Eicher, Eva Mae, 1965-1979; 8 folders (97 items) (Box 8)
    Biographical and personal data; Cytogenetics; Genetics -- Ephestia; Mouse genetics; Publication; Recommendations; Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory; University of Rochester
  - Ellefson, John, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Encyclopedia of Science and Technology (Box 8)
  - Ephestia, 4 folders (Box 8)
    - Bibliography, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Electrophoresis data (Box 8)
    - Stick list, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Erlenmeyer-Kimling, L., 1962-1973; 3 folders (28 items) (Box 8)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biographical and personal data; Fellowships, assistantships; Human genetics; Publication
  - Fabergæ, Alex C., 1971 (Box 8)
  - Falke, Ernest V., 1964 (Box 8)
  - Fechheimer, N. S., 1972 (Box 8)
  - Firsheim, William, 1960-1972; 2 folders (43 items) (Box 8)
    Bacterial genetics; Biographical and personal data; Molecular genetics; Recommendations; Wesleyan University
  - Ford, Donald H., 1968 (Box 8)
  - Forrest, Fred M., 1974 (Box 8)
  - Fox, Allen S., 1961-1976 (Box 9)
  - Freedman, Daniel G., 1962 (Box 9)
  - Friedman, Henry (Box 9)
  - Frost, Justin, 1960-1967 (Box 9)
  - Gardner, Richard, 1976-1977 (Box 9)
  - Gay, Helen, 1958-1961 (Box 9)
  - Genetic Organization, volume II, 1968-1974; 7 folders (132 items); Caspari, Ernst W.; Ravin, Arnold (Box 9)
    Editorial matters; Genetics; Publication
  - Genetics, 1963-1973; 4 folders (65 items) (Box 9)
    Editorial matters -- Genetics; Genetics Society of America; Publication -- Genetics; Referee's report; University of Rochester
    - Folder #1, 1963-1967 (Box 9)
    - Folder #2, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
    - Folder #3, 1968-1972 (Box 9)
    - Folder #4, 1972-1973 (Box 9)
  - Genetics Group of Upper New York State, 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Genetics Society of America, 1964-1967; 126 items (Box 9)
    American Institute of Biological Sciences; Conferences and symposia; Genetics Society of America; Genetics Society of America -- Committee activities; Genetics Society of America -- President; Russian politics and science; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Astaurov, B. L. (Box 9)
    - Avery, Amos G. (Box 9)
    - Botanical Society of America (Box 9)
    - Clark, Kenneth E. (Box 9)
    - Crow, James S. (Box 9)
    - Dobzhansky, Theodosius (Box 9)
    - Doermann, A. H. (Box 9)
    - Elliot, David C. (Box 9)
    - Emerson, Sterling (Box 9)
    - Fox, Allen (Box 9)
    - Gagnebin, F. (Box 9)
    - Green, Melvin M. (Box 9)
    - Jaap, R. C. (Box 9)
    - James, Edwin (Box 9)
    - Kaufmann, Berwind P. (Box 9)
    - Lerner, I. Michael (Box 9)
    - Lewis, E. B., 2 folders (Box 9)
    - National Academy of Sciences (Box 9)
    - Novitski, Edward (Box 9)
    - Owen, Ray D. (Box 9)
    - Perkins, David (Box 9)
    - Plough, Harold H. (Box 9)
    - Rogers, Stanfield (Box 9)
    - Russell, W. L. (Box 9)
    - Satina, Sophie (Box 9)
    - Sherman, Fred (Box 9)
    - Sparrow, Arnold H. (Box 9)
    - Strauss, Bernard S. (Box 9)
    - Thibault, Edward (Box 9)
    - Wagner, Robert P. (Box 9)
    - Woodward, D. O. (Box 9)
  - Ghista, Dhanjoo N., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Giles, Norman H., 1972 (Box 9)
  - Ginsburg, Benson E., 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - Glass, Bentley, 1968, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Goldhaber, Gertrude (Box 9)
  - Goldman, Mike, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Goodrich, Hubert B., 1945-1954; 5 folders (109 items) (Box 9-10)
    Biographical and personal data; Conferences and symposia; Educational matters; Research support; Teaching; Wesleyan University; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Gottesman, Irving I., 1971 (Box 10)
    Shockley, William
  - Gottlieb, Frederick Jay, 1962-1978; 3 folders (46 items) (Box 10)
    Biographical and personal data; Drosophila genetics; Genetics -- Ephestia; Publication; Recommendations; University of Pittsburgh
  - Graham, Julia, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Grahn, Douglas, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Granick, Sam, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Grants: AEC (Box 10)
    - Grants: AEC, 1961-1970; 2 folders (71 items) (Box 10)
      Atomic Energy Commission; Genetics -- Ephestia; Mouse genetics; Research support -- Proposals; Research support -- Reports
      - Grants: AEC. Folder #1, 1961-1968 (Box 10)
        Re: Somatic mutations in moth Ephestia.
      - Grants: AEC. Folder #2, 1967-1970 (Box 10)
    - Proposal, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Proposal and progress report, 1st renewal, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Proposal and progress report, 2nd renewal, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Proposal for 3rd renewal, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Proposal for 4th renewal, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Proposal for 5th renewal, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Proposal for 6th renewal, 1967; 2 folders (Box 10)
      Re: Mutations to sex-linked lethals in the mouse.
    - Proposal for 7th renewal, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Proposal for 8th renewal, 1969 (Box 10)
    - Proposal for 9th renewal, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Report on research, 1961-1964; 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Report on research, 1964-1965; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Report on research, 1964-1967; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Report on research, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
    - Report on research, 1967 (Box 10)
      Re: Measurement of sex-linked lethals in mouse.
    - Report on research, 1967-1968 (Box 10)
    - Report on research, 1967-1970; 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Report on research, 1968-1969; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Report on research, 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Grants: NIH (Box 11)
    - Grants: NIH, 1960-1961 (Box 11)
      Re: Variability in enzyme activity in inbred mouse strains.
    - Grants: NIH, 1960-1961; 3 folders (Box 11)
      Re: Behavior of the cytoplasm in populations.
    - Grants: NIH, 1965 (Box 11)
      Re: Genic action in development.
    - Grants: NIH, 1965-1967; 2 folders (Box 11)
      Re: Pleiotropism at the A locus of Ephestia.
    - Grants: NIH, 1967-1970; 5 folders (Box 11)
      Re: Gene action on eye pigment development of Ephestia.
    - Grants: NIH, 1974-1977 (Box 11)
      Re: Developmental effects of an early lethal gene in the mouse.
    - Research training, 1968-1971 (Box 11)
  - Grants: NSF, 1957-1971; 3 folders (139 items) (Box 11)
    Re: Genetic control of competence for pigment formation in the moth Ephestia.
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Educational matters -- Training grants; Embryology, developmental genetics; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics -- Ephestia; Molecular genetics; Mouse genetics; National Science Foundation; Publication; Research support -- Proposals; Research support -- Reports
    - Folder #1, 1957-1959 (Box 11)
    - Folder #2, 1959-1960 (Box 11)
    - Folder #3, 1960-1971 (Box 11)
  - Green, Melvin M., 1948-1955; 1964-1968; 41 items (Box 11)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory -- Board of Directors; Drosophila genetics; Genetics -- Ephestia; Recommendations; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Grosch, Daniel S., 1960 (Box 11)
  - Grun, Paul, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Guttman, Ruth, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
  - Haldane, J. B. S., 1955-1964 (Box 11)
  - Halsey, A. H., 1962-1963 (Box 11)
  - Hamburg, David A., 1960-1974; 30 items (Box 11)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biographical and personal data; Fellowships, assistantships; Human evolution, physical anthropology
  - Handbook of Genetics, 1971-1975 (Box 11)
  - Hartman, Philip E., 1969-1975 (Box 11)
  - Haskins, Caryl P., 1955-1959 (Box 12)
  - Heininger, Clarence G. (Box 12)
  - Henke, Karl, 1935-1956; 20 items (Box 12)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Drosophila genetics; Genetics -- Ephestia; Kuhn, Alfred; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Hilgartner, C. A. (Box 12)
    - Hilgartner, C. A., 1970-1977 (Box 12)
    - "Metabolic 'Control' in Mature Erythrocytes" (Box 12)
  - Hirsh, Jerry, 1959-1972 (Box 12)
  - Hoenigsberg, Hugo, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Hoffman, Harold A., 1973 (Box 12)
  - Hollaender, Alexander, 1961-1964 (Box 12)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1966-1967 (Box 12)
  - Imberski, Richard B., 1966-1979; 27 items (Box 12)
    Biographical and personal data; Publication; Recommendations
  - Immelmann, Klaus, 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Ingle, Dwight J., 1960 (Box 12)
  - International Biographical Archives and Dictionary of Central European Emigres, 1933-1945 (Box 12)
  - International Congress of Genetics, 14th (Moscow, Russia), 1974-1978; 2 folders (44 items) (Box 12)
    International Congress of Genetics -- Fourteenth Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Organizing Committee; Russian politics and science
  - Interamerican Congress of Psychology -- XV Congress, 1974 (Box 12)
  - International Conference on Unity of Science (Box 12)
    - 5th Conference, 1976 (Box 12)
    - 6th Conference, 1977 (Box 12)
    - 7th Conference, 1978; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - 8th Conference, 1979 (Box 12)
  - International Institute of Embryology (Box 12)
  - Invitations Refused (Box 12)
  - Ioannou, Panyiotis, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Isaacs, Harod R., 1967-1968 (Box 12)
  - Jackson Memorial Lab, Bar Harbor, 1961-1976; 2 folders (37 items) (Box 12)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Mouse genetics; Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory
  - Jain, Subodth, 1969 (Box 12)
  - James, H. Thomas, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Jauhar, Prem P., 1975 (Box 12)
  - Jauker, Friedrich W., 1977 (Box 12)
  - John, Rosemari, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Jolchir, Alan, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Kahn, Patti, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Kaudewitz, F., 1976 (Box 12)
  - Kaufmann, Berwind P., 1962 (Box 12)
  - Keeler, Clyde E., 1968 (Box 12)
  - Kikkawa, Hideo, 1953, 1958 (Box 12)
  - Kitani, Yoshiaki, 1973-1978 (Box 12)
  - Klingmuller, Walter, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Klopfer, Peter H., 1960-1961 (Box 12)
  - Knapp, Edgar, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Konyukhov, Boris V., 1975-1977 (Box 12)
  - Kraus, O., 1975 (Box 12)
  - Re. Krivshenko, Jakov, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Kroeger, H., 1958 (Box 12)
  - Krone, W., 1976 (Box 12)
  - Kuhn, Alfred, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Kuhn, Alfred, 1936-1968; 2 folders (72 items) (Box 12)
      Biographical and personal data; Embryology, developmental genetics -- Lectures, public speaking; Genetics -- Ephestia; Mouse genetics; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Lectures on Developmental Physiology, 1964-1968; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Kunkel, Beverly W., 1938-1966; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Kurth, G., 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Lasagna, Louis, 1972 (Box 13)
  - Laven, Hannes, 1958 (Box 13)
  - Lee, Geoffrey, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
  - Lehigh University, 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Lehrman, Daniel S., 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Lewin, Benjamin, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Lewin, Herbert, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Lewis, Susan E., 1976 (Box 13)
  - Lewontin, Richard C., 1979 (Box 13)
  - Lichter, R., 1975 (Box 13)
  - Lissouba, Pascal, 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Little, C. C., 1940 (Box 13)
  - Lockshin, Richard A., 1975 (Box 13)
  - Lobbecke, Ernst Arnold, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Long Island Biological Association, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Long Island Biological Association, 1961 (Box 13)
    - Biological Lab.; Present and Future, 1958 (Box 13)
  - Love, Merton R., 1964 (Box 13)
  - McClintock, Barbara, 1955-1973 (Box 13)
  - McDaniel, Robert G., 1970 (Box 13)
  - McLaren, Anne, 1973-1976 (Box 13)
  - Macmillan Co., 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Malogolowkin, Chana, 1962-1964 (Box 13)
  - Marshak, R. E. -- "Nature of the Soviet Scientific Challenge", 1957 (Box 13)
  - Maas, Ray J., 1966 (Box 13)
  - Mattson, Pat, 1970-1971 (Box 13)
  - Maxson, Stephen Clark, 1978 (Box 13)
  - May, Eduard, 1955 (Box 13)
  - Mayr, Ernst, 1947-1970; 3 folders (36 items) (Box 13)
    Evolution; Invitations; Population genetics; Publication
  - Melchers, Georg, 1969-1976; 15 items (Box 13)
    Biographical and personal data; Genetics -- Somatic hybrids; History of biology, especially genetics; Photographs; Timofeeff-Ressovsky, Nikolai W.
  - Middleton, Richard B., 1971 (Box 13)
  - Milano, Ann and Madelyn, 1960-1963; 5 folders (77 items) (Box 13)
    Biographical and personal data; Genetics -- Ephestia; Graduate study; Recommendations
  - Milkman, Roger, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
  - Miller, Harry C., 1970-1973; 3 folders (23 items) (Box 13)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Human genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Mishra, N. C., 1976-1979 (Box 13)
  - Muth, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1961-1970; 7 folders (95 items) (Box 13)
    Biographical and personal data; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics -- Ephestia; Publication; Recommendations; Requests for aid in finding positions; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; University of Koln; University of Rochester
  - Nardi, James, 1975-1978 (Box 13)
  - Nathan, Helene A., 1961 (Box 13)
  - National Institute of Health, 1961-1964 (Box 13)
  - National Institute of Mental Health, 1960-1970 (Box 13)
  - National Research Council (Box 13)
    - National Research Council, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Committee on Basic Research in Education, 1970-1973; 10 folders (112 items) (Box 13)
      Behavioral genetics, IQ; Conferences and symposia; Educational matters; National Research Council -- Committee activities; Research support
  - National Science Foundation (Box 13)
    - National Science Foundation, 1960-1975 (Box 13)
    - Biological Sciences Curriculum Study, 1964 (Box 13)
    - Fellowships Evaluation Board, 1960-1965 (Box 13)
  - Nawa, Saburo, 1961-1972; 4 folders (71 items) (Box 13)
    Biographical and personal data; Fellowships, assistantships -- University of Rochester; Genetics -- Ephestia; Molecular genetics; Publication; Recommendations
  - Nayar, N. M., 1972 (Box 13)
  - Nebert, Daniel W., 1974-1978 (Box 13)
  - Neel, James V., 1972 (Box 13)
  - Nelson, Oliver E., 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - New England Psychological Association, 1964-1965; 24 items (Box 13)
    Conferences and symposia; Invitations
  - Newton, Miriam, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Nga, Been Hen, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Nupponen, Margaret Y., 1973 (Box 14)
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Obrecht, Dean H., 1969 (Box 14)
  - Oliverio, Alberto, 1975-1977; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Omenn, Gilberg S., 1971-1977 (Box 14)
  - Ottensoo___, Fritz ?, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Otis, Arthur, 1962 (Box 14)
  - Paigen, Kenneth, 1951-1974; 4 folders (61 items) (Box 14)
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Cytogenetics; Mouse genetics; Publication; Recommendations
  - Parker, Evelyn D., 1969-1974; 27 items (Box 14)
    Biographical and personal data; Fellowships, assistantships; Publication; Recommendations
  - Parsons, Peter A., 1973-1980 (Box 14)
  - Peacock, Julia, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Perkins, David D., 1973-1979 (Box 15)
  - Perlman, Philip S., 1974 (Box 15)
  - Photographs (Box 15)
  - Piechota, Charles L., 1975 (Box 15)
  - Piepho, Hans, 1960-1975; 13 items (Box 15)
    Biographical and personal data; Embryology, developmental genetics; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics -- Ephestia; Invitations
  - Pierce, Barbara Lee, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Pirchner, F, 1976 (Box 15)
  - Pohley, Heinz-Joachim, 1958-1968; 3 folders (62 items) (Box 15)
    Embryology, developmental genetics; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics -- Ephestia; University of Rochester; Wesleyan University
  - Polgar, Steven, 1964 (Box 15)
  - Poulson, David F., 1956, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Proposal for Uniform Nomenclature in Bacterial Genetics (Box 15)
  - Psychological Reports, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Quastley, Henry, 1957 (Box 15)
  - Ramp, David ?, 1978 (Box 15)
  - Ravin, Arnold W., 1968-1978 (Box 15)
  - Recommendations, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Adams, Morton S. (Box 15)
    - Allen, Gordon (Box 15)
    - Battin, William (Box 15)
    - Berry, Spencer J. (Box 15)
    - Bergman, Allyn (Box 15)
    - Brisbin, Lehr (Box 15)
    - Buchert, Jason G. (Box 15)
    - Champlin, Arthur (Box 15)
    - Chovnic, Arthur (Box 15)
    - Cleary, Paul P. (Box 15)
    - Curtis, Robin Livingstone (Box 15)
    - Eicher, Eva M. (Box 15)
    - Erlenmeyer-Kimling, L. (Box 15)
    - Fox, Allen S. (Box 15)
    - Friedman, Linda (Box 15)
    - Graham, Julia (Box 15)
    - Gottlieb, Frederick J. (Box 15)
    - Gross, Paul (Box 15)
    - Jauker, Friedrich W. (Box 15)
    - Kafer-Boothroyd, Etta (Box 15)
    - Kayajanin, Gary (Box 15)
    - Kessler, Seymour (Box 15)
    - Kiefer, Barry (Box 15)
    - Lorick, Gloria (Box 15)
    - McCLearn, Gerald E. (Box 15)
    - Miller, Leo (Box 15)
    - Mitchell, Robert A. (Box 15)
    - Morrill, John B. (Box 15)
    - Oeschger, Joan Spalding (Box 15)
    - Parsons, Peter A. (Box 15)
    - Pearman, J. P. T. (Box 15)
    - Purdue University (Box 15)
    - Rockwell, Robert (Box 15)
    - Saul, Stephen (Box 15)
    - Schwinck, Lotte (Box 15)
    - Seiger, Marvin B. (Box 15)
    - Sondhi, K. C. (Box 15)
    - Spiess, Eliot (Box 15)
    - Stableford, Louis T. (Box 15)
    - Stinson, Harry (Box 15)
    - Stubbe, Wilfried (Box 15)
    - Thompson, William Robert (Box 15)
    - University of Michigan (Box 15)
    - Walden, David B. (Box 15)
    - Wasburn, Sherwood L. (Box 15)
    - Weitkamp, Lowell R. (Box 15)
  - Research Assistants, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Betlem, Sue (Box 15)
    - Chaplin, Elizabeth S. (Box 15)
    - Mina, Rami (Box 15)
    - Neidenbach, Diane Emlyn (Box 15)
    - Ridgeway, Tatiana (Box 15)
    - Stark, Elizabeth (Box 15)
    - Teicher, Luzx, Mrs. (Box 15)
  - Research Info Requests (Box 15)
    - Drugs, 1963-1967 (Box 15)
    - Ephestia and Drosophila, 1961-1964; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - General, 1961-1968; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Mouse Strains (Box 16)
  - Richard, A. Glenn, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Rick, Charles M., 1967 (Box 16)
  - Risen, Austin H., 1960 (Box 16)
  - Rockefeller Institute, 1962-1966 (Box 16)
  - Rockwell, Robert F., 1974 (Box 16)
  - Roe, Anne, 1968-1972 (Box 16)
  - Robbelen, G., 1975-1978 (Box 16)
  - Romano, John, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Roper, Alan, 1959 (Box 16)
  - Rosenzweig, Mark R., 1979 (Box 16)
  - Roth, Lorraine, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Rothebuhler, Walter C., 1958, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Rowley, Peter T., 1976 (Box 16)
  - Russell, Elizabeth S., 1976-1979 (Box 16)
  - Sabour, Mohammad, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Sames, Richard W. (Box 16)
  - Sapir, Philip, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Saul, George B., III, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Saul, Stephen H., 1972 (Box 16)
  - Scandalios, John, 1968, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Schaeffer, Bobb (Box 16)
  - Schwemmle, Julius, 1968 (Box 16)
  - Schaller, F., 1965 (Box 16)
  - Schilcher, Florian Von, 1977 (Box 16)
  - Scholl (Box 16)
  - Scholtissek, Christopher, 1977-1978 (Box 16)
  - Schroder, J. H., 1971-1980 (Box 16)
  - Schwartz, Victor, 1956-1975 (Box 16)
  - Schwarz, Ernst, 1932-1964; 9 folders (174 items) (Box 16)
    Biographical and personal data; Displaced German scholars; Genetics; Mouse genetics; Poultry genetics; Publication; Rabbit genetics; Rat genetics; Requests for aid in finding positions; Smithsonian Institution; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Seiger, Marvin B., 1965-1978; 7 folders (76 items) (Box 16)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biographical and personal data; Fellowships, assistantships; Political issues; Population genetics; Publication; Research support; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Sengun, Atif, 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Shapiro, Stuart, 1974-1975 (Box 17)
  - Sharp, Marjorie S., 1971 (Box 17)
  - Silagi, Selma (Box 16)
  - Simon, Lee Don, 1966 (Box 17)
  - Singleton, W. Ralph, 1964 (Box 17)
  - Smith, T. L., 1959 (Box 17)
  - Snell, George D., 1941-1952, 1976-1979; 4 folders (60 items) (Box 17)
    Cancer, chemotherapy; Editorial matters; Immunogenetics; Mouse genetics; Publication; Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory
  - Social Science Research Council. Committee on Genetics and Behavior, 1961-1965, 1980; 5 folders (59 items) (Box 17)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Conferences and symposia; Social Science Research Council -- Committee activities; Solicitations for support or contribution; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Sokoloff, Alexander, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Sonneborn, Tracy M., 1947-1951, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Source Book in the History of Science, 1961-1965; 2 folders; Caspari, Ernst W. (Box 17)
    Biographical and personal data -- Mayr, Ernst; Editorial matters; History of biology, especially genetics; Publication
  - Spalek, John M., 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - Spieth, Herman T., 1970 (Box 17)
  - Springer-Verlag N.Y., Inc., 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Stableford, Louis T., 1961-1963 (Box 17)
  - Stadler, David R., 1971-1973; 36 items (Box 17)
    Committee activities; Editorial matters
  - Stafford, Richard E., 1970 (Box 17)
  - Stanley, Julian C., 1967 (Box 17)
  - Stebbins, G. Ledyard, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Stent, Gunther Siegmund, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Stenzhorn, Hans-Jurgen, 1975 (Box 17)
  - Stern, Curt, 1946-1970; 3 folders (57 items) (Box 17)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Publication; Recommendations
  - Stocker, Bruce, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Strodach, George K., 1958 (Box 17)
  - Stroeva, O. G., 1973-1977 (Box 17)
  - Stumpf, Hildegard, 1965-1967 (Box 17)
  - Sundaramurthy, V. T., 1969 (Box 17)
  - Syracuse University -- Impressions of the Zoology Department, 1959 (Box 17)
  - Tamis, Robert H., 1958-1963 (Box 17)
  - Tantawy, Azim O., 1969 (Box 17)
  - Taschdjian, E., 1960-1961 (Box 17)
  - Teicher, Luz S., 1972-1978; 3 folders (57 items) (Box 17)